Guide to the Harriet Wasserman Literary Agency Records, 1940s-2000 and undated (bulk 1978-1995) RL.00509
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Financial Papers Series, A-Z, 1944-1994.
  - McDermott, Alice:
    - 1980-1981 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
    - 1980-1990, 2 folders (Box FR-3)
  - McDonough, Tom, 1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
  - Milbauer, Barbara, 1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
  - Mooney, Edward C., 1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
  - Myers, Walter D., 1973-1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
  - Naumoff, Lawrence, 1988-1990 (Box FR-3)
  - Peters, Natasha, 1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
  - Pietsch, Paul, 1979 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-3)
  - Price, Reynolds: (Box FR-4)
    - 1957-1966 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
    - 1968-1978 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
    - 1973-1980, 2 folders (Box FR-4)
  - Seuling, Barbara, 1974-1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
  - Sheraton, Mimi, 1979 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
  - Taliaferro, Margaret, 1978 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
  - Tax, Meredith, 1979-1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
  - Underwood, Michael, 1978-1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
  - Various authors, 1976-1977, one document (Box FR-4)
  - Vreuls, Diane, 1975-1979 (Russell and Volkening contracts) (Box FR-4)
  - Wasserman, Harriet, 1991 (Box FR-4)
  - Williams, Jay, 1964-1980 (Russell and Volkening contracts, 2 folders (Box FR-4)
- Writings Series, A-Z, 1941-1995
  The Writings Series is divided into three subseries, Restricted, Open, and Books (open). Restricted and Open subseries were arranged according to the terms described in the Processing Note and Restrictions. Internal information as well as external databases and bibliographies were used to determine the publication status of works as of Fall, 1996. Since the restrictions status of works will change after this list is printed, as works are published or as researchers locate publication information not found during processing, researchers should bring such information to the attention of Special Collections Staff as needed.
  - Writings (Restricted) Subseries, A-Z, 1940s-1995 and undated
    This subseries consists of versions of works which could not be determined to have been published. Included are a few handwritten drafts, many typescripts, and many stages of proofs. Items are arranged alphabetically by title under each author. Where multiple versions of titles exist, they are arranged to the extent determinable in chronological order of composition. ENTIRE SUBSERIES IS RESTRICTED.
    - Amoss, Berthe (Box WR-1)
      - Burn the Witch, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-1)
      - Ten Days in Costa Rica, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Through the Cotswolds by Bicycle, ca. 1977 (Box WR-1)
    - Anderson, Scott
      - Bernie Sanders goes to Washington, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Darker Shade of Pale, 1991 (Box WR-1)
      - Odyssey of a Wop: The Life and Times Of John Fante, undated (Box WR-1)
    - Auerbach, John
      - My Captain and I, undated, 3 folders (Box WR-1)
      - A Strange Story, 1988 October (Box WR-1)
    - Bausch, Richard
      - A Bachelor's Tale, ca. 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - A Common Instance, ca. 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - Devotions, ca. 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - A Domestic Education, ca. 1977 and undated, 2 folders (Box WR-1)
      - An Election, undated (Box WR-1)
      - The Evening Performance, 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - Everyday Life, 1977, 2 versions (Box WR-1)
      - The Man Who Should Have Studied Business, 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - On the Way There, 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - Single, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-1)
      - The Six Unfinished Stories of Millicent Stark, ca. 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - Snows, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-1)
      - Someone To Watch Over Me, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Staying Warm, 1977 (Box WR-1)
      - The Summer Before the Wars, ca. 1982 and undated, 2 versions in 3 folders (Box WR-1)
      - This Just Man, undated (Box WR-1)
      - The Trouble Between Us, undated, 1 version in 2 folders (Box WR-1)
      - Untitled (autobiographical), undated (Box WR-1)
      - Untitled (fragment of a novel, pp. 309-321), undated (Box WR-1)
      - Wisemen at their End, undated (Box WR-1)
    - Bellow, Adam
      - Role-Playing in the Bush, undated (Box WR-1)
    - Bellow, Saul
      - Arion Article about William Arrowsmith, 1993 January (Box WR-1)
      - Article for the National Interest, undated (Box WR-1)
      - All Marbles Still Accounted For, 1992 and undated, 2 folders (Box WR-1)
      - Cook County Hospital, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Fellows Conference Speech, Washington, DC., undated (Box WR-1)
      - Goethe Essay, 1978 (Box WR-1)
      - A Jewish Writer in America, 1988 April (Box WR-1)
      - Unpublished Manuscripts (list of works), 1940s - 1960s; undated (Box WR-1)
      - Miami Speech, undated (Box WR-1)
      - The Next Necessary Thing, 1967 (Box WR-1)
      - The Speaking and Writing of Words, 1983 May 25 (Box WR-1)
      - Untitled Essay, 1986 July 7 (Box WR-1)
      - Untitled Fragments, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-1)
    - Biddle, Wayne
      - Bloody Business: A Corporate History of Defense Spending from World War I to Star Wars, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Darkside of the Moon, undated (Box WR-1)
      - The Fortunes of Chemical War, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Saudi Arabia Proposal, undated (Box WR-1)
      - The Silicon Underworld, undated (Box WR-1)
      - Tracks, ca. 1978 (Box WR-1)
      - Twelve Men and the Moon Profiles of Apollo Workers, ca. 1988-1989 (Box WR-1)
    - Birnbaum, Phyllis
      - Passion and Repentance, undated (translation of Iro zange by Chiyo Uno), 1 version in 2 folders (Box WR-1)
    - Bloomstein, Henry (Box WR-2)
      - Suder, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Sushi Without Fear, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Brodsky-Koperwas, Evelyn
      - The Moon Child, 1983 (Box WR-2)
    - Brown, Jo Giese
      - Jo's Baby, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Brown Wesley
      - The Saga of Society Red: The Autobiography of Dexter Gordon, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Buechner, Frederick
      - HBS 1838-1920, undated (Box WR-2)
      - A Novelist Looks at The Bible, undated (Box WR-2)
      - The Schroeders Revisited, 1994 April 4 (Box WR-2)
    - Cable, Mary
      - Article Ideas, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Biography of Dr. James J. Waring, undated, 1 version in 2 folders (Box WR-2)
    - Cameron, Sara
      - Camouflage, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Clark, Eleanor
      - Solstice Weather, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Cleaver, Anastasia
      - The Rasputin Effect, undated (Box WR-2)
      - A Tyranny of Roses, 1985 (undated proposal and 1985 draft), 1 version in 5 folders (Box WR-2)
    - Darron, Ellen
      - The Lunch Letters, undated (Box WR-2)
      - No Gentleness, undated (Box WR-2)
    - DeHaven, Tom
      - Don Juan and the X-Ray Kid: a Film Treatment, 1985 (Box WR-2)
    - Delving, Michael (N.B.: pseudonym of Jay Williams)
      - Gourmandizing in Gloucestershire, undated (Box WR-2)
      - These Wild Hills, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Dubrow, Marsha
      - Capitol Hell, 1984 (Box WR-2)
    - Feller, Howard
      - For Old Time's Sake, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Flanagan, Dennis
      - A Capital Offense: Outline, 1990 June 14 (Box WR-2)
    - Gertler, T. (Box WR-2)
    - Glickfeld, Carole
      - Blue Lint, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Bursting Joy's Grape: The Miseries of Publishing, undated (Box WR-2)
      - The City That Swallowed New York, ca. 1990 (Box WR-2)
      - Dancing in the Dark, ca. 1988 (Box WR-2)
      - The Devil's Guest, undated (Box WR-2)
      - This Goldeneh Medina, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Going for the Second Thirty, undated (Box WR-2)
      - If You Think You're Mrs. Berrigan, ca. 1990 (Box WR-2)
      - No Useful Purpose, undated (Box WR-2)
      - The Other Marilyn, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Predictable Moves, ca. 1990 (Box WR-2)
      - Slice of Life, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Somethin' Be Different, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Tornado Watch, 1990 and undated, 2 folders (Box WR-2)
      - Untitled, undated (novel fragment?) (Box WR-2)
    - Goldstein, Rebecca
      - Contrary Winds, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Flugel's Final Truth, undated (Box WR-2)
      - untitled (Box WR-2)
    - Greenwald, Sheila
      - Characters in Real Life, undated (Box WR-2)
      - Halloween Rosy, undated (Box WR-2)
    - Greenwald, Sheila (continued) (Box WR-3)
      - Maud's Book, undated (Box WR-3)
      - What's a Thirteen Year Old To Do, undated (Box WR-3)
    - Hassler, Jon
      - Along the Road from Inch to Knock, ca. 1977 (Box WR-3)
      - The Book of Brendan, undated, 1 version in 3 folders (Box WR-3)
      - Christopher, Moony, and the Birds, undated (Box WR-3)
      - A Dublin Sketch, undated (Box WR-3)
      - Plum, 1985 February 18, 1 version in 2 folders (Box WR-3)
      - A Portrait of the Novelist as a Young Man, ca. 1980 (Box WR-3)
      - Rufus at the Door, ca. 1980 (Box WR-3)
      - The Stillness at Walden Pond, ca. 1977 (Box WR-3)
      - Yesterday's Garbage, undated (Box WR-3)
    - Heller, Erica
      - The Bimbo Handbook, undated (Box WR-3)
      - Cannibals on Ice, 1990-1991, 3 versions (Box WR-3)
      - Cold Shoulder, 1991 September 18 (Box WR-3)
      - Midnight at the Banana Stand, 1989 (Box WR-3)
      - Untitled, undated (Box WR-3)
    - Hijuelos, Oscar
      - Mr. Ives' Christmas, 1994-1995 and undated, 11 versions in 12 folders (Box WR-3)
        CLOSED during the lifetimes of Hijuelos and Wasserman
    - Hijuelos, Oscar (continued) (Box WR-4)
      - Mr. Ives' Christmas, 1994-1995 and undated, 11 versions in 12 folders (Box WR-4)
    - Horwitz, James
      - Magic Carpet, undated (Box WR-4)
      - The Last Adventure on the Orient Express, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Tunisia: An Arabesque Kaleidoscope, undated (Box WR-4)
    - Humphreys, Josephine
      - Happiness in the Coming Year, ca. 1986 (Box WR-4)
    - Huttman, Barbara
      - Peddling Your Book(proposal), undated (Box WR-4)
    - Jhabvala, Ruth
      - Abode of Peace, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Between Two Women, ca. 1975 (Box WR-4)
      - A Call from the East, ca. 1981 (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled Speech, undated (Box WR-4)
    - Josephson, Erland
      - Stages and Screens, undated (Box WR-4)
    - Kennan George
      - Cyon Manuscript, 1985 July, 2 folders (Box WR-4)
      - General tenor of remarks made at private dinner, New York City, October 9, 1984, 2 folders (Box WR-4)
      - Lecture for 10-13 in Washington, 1994 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks at award banquet of the Physicians for Social Responsibility, 1988 March 5 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks at 40th Anniversary Celebration of the Policy Planning Staff, Washington, D.C.: U.S.-Soviet Relations: Containment as a Prerequisite for Accommodation, 1987 May 11 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks at Trinity Church Forum: Russian and American Aberrations: A Conversation with George Kennan, 1985 June 2 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks before the Council on Foreign Relations, December 20, 1989 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks for Friday, January 10, 1992, Institute for Advanced Study (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks for IN CONCERT sponsored by Musicians Against Nuclear Arms, 1983 October 24 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks for reception given by the Slavonic Division of the New York Library on March 11, 1987 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks made at the November 5 concert at the Institute for Advanced Study, 1983 (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks to be made at the installation ceremony for Fred Starr as President of Oberlin College, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Remarks in presenting to Senator Claiborne Pell the Award of the American Academy-Institute of Arts and Letters for Distinguished Service to the Arts, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Review of Gene Sharp's Making Europe Unconquerable, 1985 (Box WR-4)
      - Security and the Moscow Embassy, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Statement, 1985 January 24 (Box WR-4)
      - Statement upon receiving Encyclopedia Britannica Award, undated (Box WR-4)
      - A Statesman's Approach to U.S.-Soviet Relations: What are the limits of diplomacy? 1985 April 3 (Box WR-4)
      - Talk at Trinity Church, Open Forum, May 1, 1983 (Box WR-4)
      - Talk given at Trinity Church Forum, January 12, 1992 (Box WR-4)
      - Ten Interview Questions for Professor Kennan, 1989 August (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled, 1993 (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled, 1994 (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled I, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled II, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled III, undated (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled article for Washington Post, 1989 November 10 (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled,(autobiographical excerpt), undated (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled, (from the Institute for Advanced Study), 1992 November 2 (Box WR-4)
      - Untitled talk at Trinity Church, undated (Box WR-4)
    - Klein, Elizabeth
      - Reconciliations, undated (Box WR-4)
    - Koperwas, Sam
      - Act Natural, undated (Box WR-4)
    - Koperwas, Sam (Box WR-5)
      - The Book of Life, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Book proposal on professional athletes, undated (Box WR-5)
      - The Businessman, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Easy Money, undated (Box WR-5)
      - The Jaguar Jungle, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Magic, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Poorboys, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Satisfaction, undated (Box WR-5)
    - Kotker, Norman
      - Headaches, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Lucky, ca. 1986 (Box WR-5)
      - Necrology, undated (Box WR-5)
    - Krahn, Fernando
      - The Administrator and the Halo and The Job, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Gil and Pola, undated (Box WR-5)
      - The McHorribles, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Miscellaneous cartoons, undated, 4 folders (Box WR-5)
    - Krieger, Joel
      - Untitled fiction, undated (Box WR-5)
    - Kuskin, Karla
      - Animal Stories--samples, ca. 1975 (Box WR-5)
      - Blue Isn't Better Than Green, ca. 1977 (Box WR-5)
      - Cat and Dog Dialogue and Here Is Hugo In His Bed, ca. 1975 (Box WR-5)
      - Hugo at Night, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Marion, ca. 1977 (Box WR-5)
      - The Particular Flower, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Poems, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Quong Song Quat Cat, ca. 1976 (Box WR-5)
      - There Was a Witch, undated (Box WR-5)
      - There Were Two Young Elephants, ca. 1977 (Box WR-5)
      - The Witch Who Watched TV, 1982 (Box WR-5)
      - The Witch Who Wanted to Go On a Midnight Ride, ca. 1975 (Box WR-5)
    - Lamm, Steven
      - Beyond Diagnosis: Forming a Partnership With Your Doctor, undated (Box WR-5)
    - Lasson, Robert
      - Do You Sincerely Want to Be Filthy Rich? undated (Box WR-5)
      - An Immodest Proposal for Draft Reform, undated (Box WR-5)
      - Heavenly Hosts, undated (Box WR-5)
      - My Little War, undated (Box WR-5)
    - Lee, Laurel
      - Barnaby and the Seed, 1979 (Box WR-5)
      - Untitled, 1992 November 18 (Box WR-5)
      - Untitled, undated (Box WR-5)
    - Levin, Phyllis
      - Mrs. Wilson Is President: The story of Woodrow and Edith Wilson, 1992 and undated, 3 versions in 4 folders (Box WR-5)
    - Litewka, Albert (Box WR-6)
      - Warsaw Kaddish, 1 version in 3 folders (Box WR-6)
    - Lob, Gayle S.
      - Marissa, undated (Box WR-6)
    - Markus, Julia
      - Angel At My Back: Proposal, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Last Time I Saw Paris, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Maybe She Go: Proposal, ca. 1980-1981 (Box WR-6)
      - Making it Snow, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Siding With Nola Neitherland: Proposal, ca. mid 1980s (Box WR-6)
      - Silvano's Dream, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-6)
      - Symptoms of he Sixties, 1983 (Box WR-6)
      - Uncle; A Play in Two Acts, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Untitled Play, undated (Box WR-6)
    - Marschall, Richard
      - Cousins: Proposal, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Whole Word of Short Wave Radio: Proposal, undated (Box WR-6)
    - McDermott, Alice
      - Box Numbers, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Dink, 1981 October 1 (Box WR-6)
      - The Happiest of Mothers, 1993 (Box WR-6)
      - His Dancer, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Jiminy, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Larry, ca. 1985 (Box WR-6)
      - The Last of the Gilhooleys, ca. 1982 (Box WR-6)
      - Painting the Trim, ca. 1980 (Box WR-6)
      - Margo, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Reasons People Marry, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Saviors, ca. 1980 (Box WR-6)
      - Troubles, undated (Box WR-6)
      - An Unremarkable Woman, ca. 1982 (Box WR-6)
      - A Victim of One's Own, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Weekend Claire Was Married, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Untitled novel in progress, 1982, 3 folders (Box WR-6)
    - McDonough, Tom
      - A Coupla Months of Living Cautiously, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Deep Wrist, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Duffyvision, undated, 2 versions 4 folders (Box WR-6)
      - Eyes for Miss Piggy, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Gunga Duke, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Heart of Dimness, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Iñigo, 1981 (Box WR-6)
      - A Jesuit Education: Last Exit To Language, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The King of Me, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Late Clone News, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Spot Where the Gangster Landed, undated (Box WR-6)
      - The Teddy Chronicles ( Steady Teddy in the Fourth Dimension and Murder in the Carwash,) undated (Box WR-6)
      - Two Guys, 1982 March 25 (Box WR-6)
    - Meyers, Mollie, and Suzanne Gerber (add x-ref)
      - Learn to Flirt, 1982 (Box WR-6)
    - Mian, Mary
      - Nantucket Mice, Ahoy! undated (Box WR-6)
    - Mooney, Ted
      - Bodyguard, 1985 January 7 (Box WR-6)
    - Mountzoures, Harry
      - A Far Cry From Home, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Fruit, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Laughter, undated (Box WR-6)
    - Mullins, Neva
      - The Devil, undated (Box WR-6)
    - Myers, Walter Dean
      - Antonio's Song, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Champions, undated (Box WR-6)
      - Études on a Sad Theme, undated (Box WR-6)
    - Myers, Walter Dean (continued) (Box WR-7)
      - Songhai! undated, 1 version in 4 folders (Box WR-7)
        See also Oversized Material (Boxes) Untitled, undated
    - Peters, Natasha (pseudonym of Anastasia Cleaver)
      - Riders on the Storm, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Price, Reynolds
      - Dream Elephants, undated (Box WR-7)
      - An Early Christmas, undated (Box WR-7)
      - A Long and Happy Life (screenplay), 1991 and undated, 2 folders (Box WR-7)
      - "Waiting at Dachau" (Box WR-7)
    - Rachlin, Nahid
      - Dark Gravity, ca. 1982 (Box WR-7)
      - Office Song, ca. 1982 (Box WR-7)
    - Seidler, Tor
      - A Romantic Family, 1 version in 2 folders (Box WR-7)
    - Seuling, Barbara
      - The New Baby, undated (Box WR-7)
      - No, No, Harold! undated, 3 folders (Box WR-7)
      - The Scary Movie, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Secrets, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Surprise Party, 1980 August 12 (Box WR-7)
      - The Teeny Meany Monster, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Various Cartoons, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Sheraton, Mimi
      - Kiss Me, You Fool, ca. 1975-1978 (Box WR-7)
    - Simon, Norma
      - When Mama Baked Pirog, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Simonds, Nina
      - Article Proposals, ca. 1984 (Box WR-7)
    - Tax, Meredith
      - Anticommunism and Literature, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Arrows of Desire: A Memoir, and The Life You Save: A Modern Romance: Proposals, 1989 and undated, 3 folders (Box WR-7)
      - Doing It the Hard Way: My Life and the Women's Movement: Proposal, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Frozen Like Lot's Wife, undated (Box WR-7)
      - The Hungry Fighter, undated (Box WR-7)
      - It's A Lovely Day Tomorrow: Proposal, 1982 March 24 (Box WR-7)
      - Jewish in Bohemia, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Kishinev, undated (Box WR-7)
      - The Life You Save, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-7)
      - Sarah Laughed: Problem Pregnancies in Older Mothers, undated (Box WR-7)
      - The Savor of Morality, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Too Old to Work, and Too Young to Die, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Underwood, Michael
      - O.K. for Murder, 1982 November 13 (Box WR-7)
    - Voll, Daniel
      - Collection of Short Stories, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Vreuls, Diane
      - The Alice P. Gamboe Strip, undated (Box WR-7)
      - The Animal Who Wanted To Fly, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Ben, undated (Box WR-7)
      - On the Feast of Malcolm, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Walter, Eugene
      - Dizzy Countries, undated, 2 folders (Box WR-7)
      - Vodka, Anyone? undated (Box WR-7)
    - Wasserman, Dick
      - A Ticket to Palookaville, Part 2, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Williams, Victoria
      - Feminist Fairy Tales: Proposal, ca. 1973 (Box WR-7)
      - A Place of My Own, ca. 1972 (Box WR-7)
      - Tam Lin, undated (Box WR-7)
    - Winslow, Joan
      - Double Vision, 1984 September 28, 1 version in 2 folders (Box WR-7)
    - Unknown Authors
      - The Good Place (title page only), 1990 July (Box WR-7)
      - Untitled note, undated (Box WR-7)
      - Untitled story, undated (Box WR-7)
  - Writings (Open) Subseries, A-Z, 1948-1995 and undated
    This subseries consists of versions of works which have been published. Included are a few handwritten drafts, many typescripts, and many stages of proofs. Items are arranged alphabetically by title under each author. Where multiple versions of titles exist, they are arranged to the extent determinable in chronological order of composition.
    - Amoss, Berthe (Box WO-1)
      - Three Book Reviews (print), 1984 April-June (Box WO-1)
    - Bausch, Richard
      - All the Way in Flagstaff, Arizona(print), undated (Box WO-1)
      - Ancient History, undated (Box WO-1)
      - Aren't You Happy For Me? undated (Box WO-1)
      - Consolation (print), 1990 March 19 (Box WO-1)
      - Contrition, undated (Box WO-1)
      - Evening, undated (Box WO-1)
      - The Eyes of Love (print), 1990 August (Box WO-1)
      - The Fireman's Wife (print), 1989 November (Box WO-1)
      - Good Evening, Mr. and Mrs. America, And All the Ships At Sea, undated, 5 versions in 7 folders (Box WO-1)
      - The Last Good Time, undated (Box WO-1)
      - Letter to the Lady of the House (print), 1989 October 23 (Box WO-1)
      - Luck (print), 1990 September (Box WO-1)
      - The Man Who Knew Belle Starr, 1987 April and 1990 September, 2 folders, print (Box WO-1)
      - The Natural Effects of Divorce, undated (Box WO-1)
      - The Person I Have Mostly Become, undated (Box WO-1)
      - Plains (became Rebel Powers), undated (Box WO-1)
      - Police Dreams (print), 1987 May (Box WO-1)
      - Rare and Endangered Species, ca. 1983, 3 folders (Box WO-1)
      - Rebel Powers, 1989-92, 3 versions in 8 folders (Box WO-1)
      - St. Agnes Eve (print), 1975 (Box WO-1)
      - Violence, 1988-1989, 3 versions in 4 folders (Box WO-1)
    - Bausch, Richard (continued) (Box WO-2)
      - Violence (continued), 1988-1992, 5 versions in 7 folders (Box WO-2)
      - Wedlock, 1990 June (Box WO-2)
      - What Feels Like the World (print), 1985 October (Box WO-2)
      - Weather, undated (Box WO-2)
    - Bellow, Saul
      See also Lillian McCall in this subseries.
      - Address at the Chicago Public Library, 1972 October, 2 folders, folder 2 print (Box WO-2)
      - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters, Acceptance Speech, 1977 May 18 (Box WO-2)
      - The Bellarosa Connection, 1988-1989, 11 folders (Box WO-2)
      - Brandeis Gold Medal Acceptance Speech, 1978 April 19 (Box WO-2)
      - Buñuel, 1962 November, 2 typescripts, from Lois Phillips files (Box WO-2)
        For further information see Correspondence (Open) Subseries, Bellow, 1985 and that subseries' note)
      - By the St. Lawrence (print), 1985 July (Box WO-2)
      - Chicago: The City That Was, The City That Is, 1986 May-October, 3 folders, folder 3 is print (Box WO-2)